<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>orioninsist - Container</title>
    <link>https://orioninsist.org/tags/container/</link>
    <description>Container RSS feed</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Docker Commands and Container Management</title>
      <link>https://orioninsist.org/project/devops/2023/2023-11/exploring-docker-commands-and-container-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 02:53:47 &#43;03</pubDate>
      <description>Introduction Docker has revolutionized the way applications are developed, deployed, and managed. It provides a lightweight and portable environment for running containers, which are self-contained instances of an application and its dependencies. Docker commands offer a powerful means to manage and interact with these containers.
Updating and Listing Container Images
The provided Bash commands demonstrate the process of updating and listing Docker container images.
sudo docker container run -it centos:7 bash sudo yum -y update ls -l This script first creates a new container based on the centos:7 image. Inside the container, it updates the system packages using the yum command. Finally, it lists the contents of the current directory.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Docker Desktop on Debian</title>
      <link>https://orioninsist.org/blog/how-to-install-docker-desktop-on-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 23:20:30 &#43;03</pubDate>
      <description>Docker is a powerful platform that allows you to develop, ship, and run applications inside containers. Installing Docker on Debian is a straightforward process, and in this guide, we&rsquo;ll walk you through the steps to get Docker Desktop up and running on your Debian-based system.
Prerequisites Before we begin, make sure you have the following prerequisites in place: A Debian-based system (such as Debian itself or Ubuntu) Administrative (sudo) privileges
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Docker</title>
      <link>https://orioninsist.org/blog/what-is-docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 11:36:05 &#43;03</pubDate>
      <description>Introduction Docker is a containerization platform that simplifies software development and deployment. It allows you to package applications and their dependencies into lightweight, portable containers. These containers ensure consistent performance across different environments.
Key Concepts Containers: Docker uses containers to encapsulate applications and dependencies, ensuring they run consistently.
Images: Docker containers are built from images, which are read-only templates containing everything needed to run an application.
Dockerfile: A Dockerfile is a script used to create Docker images, specifying the application and its environment.
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
